<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- Field: Doc-Info; Name: Generator; Value: GoXBRL; Version: 5.2a -->
<!-- Field: Doc-Info; Name: VendorURI; Value: http://www.novaworks.co -->
<!-- Field: Doc-Info; Name: Source; Value: ck0001547950%2D20200224.xfr; Date: 2020%2D02%2D28T04:24:27Z -->
<!-- Field: Doc-Info; Name: Status; Value: 0x80010000 -->
<xbrl>
  <schemaRef href="ck0001547950-20200224.xsd" type="simple"/>
  <context id="AsOf2020-02-24">
    <entity>
      <identifier scheme="http://www.sec.gov/CIK">0001547950</identifier>
    </entity>
    <period>
      <startDate>2020-02-24</startDate>
      <endDate>2020-02-24</endDate>
    </period>
  </context>
  <context id="AsOf2020-02-24_custom_S000067182Member">
    <entity>
      <identifier scheme="http://www.sec.gov/CIK">0001547950</identifier>
      <segment>
        <explicitMember dimension="dei:LegalEntityAxis">ck0001547950:S000067182Member</explicitMember>
      </segment>
    </entity>
    <period>
      <startDate>2020-02-24</startDate>
      <endDate>2020-02-24</endDate>
    </period>
  </context>
  <context id="AsOf2020-02-24_custom_S000067182Member_custom_C000216128Member">
    <entity>
      <identifier scheme="http://www.sec.gov/CIK">0001547950</identifier>
      <segment>
        <explicitMember dimension="dei:LegalEntityAxis">ck0001547950:S000067182Member</explicitMember>
        <explicitMember dimension="rr:ProspectusShareClassAxis">ck0001547950:C000216128Member</explicitMember>
      </segment>
    </entity>
    <period>
      <startDate>2020-02-24</startDate>
      <endDate>2020-02-24</endDate>
    </period>
  </context>
  <unit id="USD">
    <measure>iso4217:USD</measure>
  </unit>
  <unit id="Ratio">
    <measure>xbrli:pure</measure>
  </unit>
  <DocumentType contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24">485BPOS</DocumentType>
  <DocumentPeriodEndDate contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24">2020-02-24</DocumentPeriodEndDate>
  <EntityRegistrantName contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24">Exchange Listed Funds Trust</EntityRegistrantName>
  <EntityCentralIndexKey contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24">0001547950</EntityCentralIndexKey>
  <EntityInvCompanyType contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24">N-1A</EntityInvCompanyType>
  <AmendmentFlag contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24">false</AmendmentFlag>
  <DocumentCreationDate contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24">2020-02-24</DocumentCreationDate>
  <DocumentEffectiveDate contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24">2020-02-24</DocumentEffectiveDate>
  <ProspectusDate contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24">2020-02-24</ProspectusDate>
  <TradingSymbol contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24_custom_S000067182Member_custom_C000216128Member">HDIV</TradingSymbol>
  <RiskReturnHeading contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24_custom_S000067182Member">QRAFT AI-Enhanced U.S. High Dividend ETF</RiskReturnHeading>
  <ObjectiveHeading contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24_custom_S000067182Member">Investment Objective</ObjectiveHeading>
  <ObjectivePrimaryTextBlock contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24_custom_S000067182Member">&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;The QRAFT AI-Enhanced U.S. High Dividend&#13;ETF (the "Fund") seeks long-term total returns through regular dividend income and capital appreciation.&lt;/p&gt;</ObjectivePrimaryTextBlock>
  <ExpenseHeading contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24_custom_S000067182Member">Fees and Expenses</ExpenseHeading>
  <ExpenseNarrativeTextBlock contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24_custom_S000067182Member">&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;This table describes the fees and expenses&#13;that you may pay if you buy and hold shares of the Fund. This table and the Example below do not include the brokerage commissions&#13;that investors may pay on their purchases and sales of shares.&lt;/p&gt;</ExpenseNarrativeTextBlock>
  <OperatingExpensesCaption contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24_custom_S000067182Member">Annual Fund Operating Expenses (expenses that you pay each year as a percentage of the value of your investment)</OperatingExpensesCaption>
  <ExpenseExampleHeading contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24_custom_S000067182Member">Example</ExpenseExampleHeading>
  <ExpenseExampleNarrativeTextBlock contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24_custom_S000067182Member">&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: center"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;This Example is intended to help you compare&#13;the cost of investing in the Fund with the cost of investing in other funds. The Example assumes that you invest $10,000 in the&#13;Fund for the time periods indicated and then sell all of your shares at the end of those periods. The Example also assumes that&#13;your investment has a 5% return each year and that the Fund's operating expenses remain the same. Although your actual costs&#13;may be higher or lower, based on these assumptions your cost would be:&lt;/p&gt;</ExpenseExampleNarrativeTextBlock>
  <PortfolioTurnoverHeading contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24_custom_S000067182Member">Portfolio Turnover</PortfolioTurnoverHeading>
  <PortfolioTurnoverTextBlock contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24_custom_S000067182Member">&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;The Fund pays transaction costs, such as&#13;commissions, when it buys and sells securities (or "turns over" its portfolio). A higher portfolio turnover rate may&#13;indicate higher transaction costs and may result in higher taxes when shares of the Fund are held in a taxable account. These costs,&#13;which are not reflected in annual fund operating expenses or in the example, affect the Fund's performance. Because the Fund&#13;is new, portfolio turnover information is not yet available.&lt;/p&gt;</PortfolioTurnoverTextBlock>
  <StrategyHeading contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24_custom_S000067182Member">Principal Investment Strategies</StrategyHeading>
  <RiskHeading contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24_custom_S000067182Member">Principal Risks</RiskHeading>
  <RiskNarrativeTextBlock contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24_custom_S000067182Member">&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;As with all funds, a shareholder is subject&#13;to the risk that his or her investment could lose money. An investment in the Fund is not a bank deposit and is not insured or&#13;guaranteed by the FDIC or any government agency. The principal risks affecting shareholders' investments in the Fund are&#13;set forth below.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;&lt;font&gt;&lt;i&gt;Common&#13;Stock Risk&lt;/i&gt;. Common stock holds the lowest priority in the capital structure of a company, and therefore takes the largest share&#13;of the company's risk and its accompanying volatility. The value of the common stock held by the Fund may fall due to general&#13;market and economic conditions, perceptions regarding the industries in which the issuers of securities held by the Fund participate,&#13;or facts relating to specific companies in which the Fund invests.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Dividend Paying Securities Risk&lt;/i&gt;.&#13;Securities that pay dividends, as a group, may be out of favor with the market and underperform the overall equity market or stocks&#13;of companies that do not pay dividends. In addition, changes in the dividend policies of the companies held by the Fund or the&#13;capital resources available for such company's dividend payments may adversely affect the Fund.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify; text-indent: -0.05pt"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify; text-indent: -0.05pt"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Issuer-Specific&#13;Risk&lt;/i&gt;. Fund performance depends on the performance of individual securities to which the Fund has exposure. Issuer-specific&#13;events, including changes in the financial condition of an issuer, can have a negative impact on the value of the Fund.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify; text-indent: -0.05pt"&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify; text-indent: -0.05pt"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Large Capitalization&#13;Risk&lt;/i&gt;. Returns on investments in securities of large companies could trail the returns on investments in securities of smaller&#13;and mid-sized companies.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify; text-indent: -0.05pt"&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Limited Authorized Participants, Market&#13;Makers and Liquidity Providers Risk&lt;/i&gt;. Because the Fund is an ETF, only a limited number of institutional investors (known as&#13;"Authorized Participants") are authorized to purchase and redeem shares directly from the Fund. In addition, there&#13;may be a limited number of market makers and/or liquidity providers in the marketplace. To the extent either of the following events&#13;occur, shares of the Fund may trade at a material discount to their net asset value ("NAV") per share and possibly&#13;face delisting: (i) Authorized Participants exit the business or otherwise become unable to process creation and/or redemption&#13;orders and no other Authorized Participants step forward to perform these services, or (ii) market makers and/or liquidity providers&#13;exit the business or significantly reduce their business activities and no other entities step forward to perform their functions.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify; text-indent: -0.05pt"&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Management Risk&lt;/i&gt;. The Fund is actively-managed&#13;and may not meet its investment objective based on the Adviser's success or failure to implement investment strategies for&#13;the Fund. The Fund's principal investment strategies are dependent upon the use of Qraft's proprietary artificial intelligence&#13;security selection process and, as a result, the Adviser's skill in understanding and utilizing such process. The achievement&#13;of the investment objective of the Fund cannot be guaranteed and the Adviser's management of the Fund may not produce the&#13;intended results.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Market Risk&lt;/i&gt;. The market price&#13;of a security or instrument could decline, sometimes rapidly or unpredictably, due to general market conditions that are not specifically&#13;related to a particular company, such as real or perceived adverse economic or political conditions throughout the world, changes&#13;in the general outlook for corporate earnings, changes in interest or currency rates or adverse investor sentiment generally.&#13;The market value of a security may also decline because of factors that affect a particular industry or industries, such as labor&#13;shortages or increased production costs and competitive conditions within an industry.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Models and Data Risk&lt;/i&gt;. The Fund relies&#13;heavily on a proprietary artificial intelligence selection model as well as data and information supplied by third parties that&#13;are utilized by such model. To the extent the model does not perform as designed or as intended, the Fund's strategy may&#13;not be successfully implemented and the Fund may lose value. If the model or data are incorrect or incomplete, any decisions made&#13;in reliance thereon may lead to the inclusion or exclusion of securities that would have been excluded or included had the model&#13;or data been correct and complete.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;&lt;font&gt;&lt;i&gt;New/Smaller&#13;Fund Risk&lt;/i&gt;. A new or smaller fund is subject to the risk that its performance may not represent how the fund is expected to&#13;or may perform in the long term. In addition, new funds have limited operating histories for investors to evaluate and new and&#13;smaller funds may not attract sufficient assets to achieve investment and trading efficiencies. There can be no assurance that&#13;the Fund will achieve an economically viable size, in which case it could ultimately liquidate. The Fund may be liquidated by the&#13;Board of Trustees without a shareholder vote. In a liquidation, shareholders of the Fund will receive an amount equal to the Fund's&#13;NAV, after deducting the costs of liquidation, including the transaction costs of disposing of the Fund's portfolio investments.&#13;Receipt of a liquidation distribution may have negative tax consequences for shareholders. Additionally, during the Fund's&#13;liquidation all or a portion of the Fund's portfolio may be invested in a manner not consistent with its investment objective&#13;and investment policies.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;&lt;font&gt;&lt;i&gt;Non-Diversification&#13;Risk&lt;/i&gt;. The Fund is a non-diversified investment company under the Investment Company Act of 1940 (the "1940 Act"),&#13;meaning that, as compared to a diversified fund, it can invest a greater percentage of its assets in securities issued by or representing&#13;a small number of issuers. As a result, the performance of these issuers can have a substantial impact on the Fund's performance.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Operational Risk&lt;/i&gt;. The Fund and its&#13;service providers may experience disruptions that arise from human error, processing and communications errors, counterparty or&#13;third-party errors, technology or systems failures, any of which may have an adverse impact on the Fund.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;&lt;font&gt;&lt;i&gt;Portfolio&#13;Turnover Risk&lt;/i&gt;. The Fund's investment strategy is expected to result in high portfolio turnover, which may result in increased&#13;transaction costs and may lower Fund performance.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;&lt;font&gt;&lt;i&gt;Sector&#13;Focus Risk&lt;/i&gt;. The Fund may invest a significant portion of its assets in one or more sectors and thus will be more susceptible&#13;to the risks affecting those sectors. While the Fund's sector exposure is expected to vary over time, the Fund anticipates&#13;that it may be subject to some or all of the risks described below. The list below is not a comprehensive list of the sectors to&#13;which the Fund may have exposure over time and should not be relied on as such.&amp;#160;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0 0pt 0.5in; text-align: justify"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Communication Services&#13;Sector Risk&lt;/i&gt;. Communication services companies are particularly vulnerable to the potential obsolescence of products and services&#13;due to technological advancement and the innovation of competitors. Companies in the communication services sector may also be&#13;affected by other competitive pressures, such as pricing competition, as well as research and development costs, substantial capital&#13;requirements and government regulation. Additionally, fluctuating domestic and international demand, shifting demographics and&#13;often unpredictable changes in consumer tastes can drastically affect a communication services company's profitability. While&#13;all companies may be susceptible to network security breaches, certain companies in the communication services sector may be particular&#13;targets of hacking and potential theft of proprietary or consumer information or disruptions in service, which could have a material&#13;adverse effect on their businesses.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0 0pt 0.5in; text-align: justify"&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0 0pt 0.5in; text-align: justify"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Consumer Discretionary&#13;Sector Risk&lt;/i&gt;. Consumer discretionary companies are companies that provide non-essential goods and services, such as retailers,&#13;media companies and consumer services. These companies manufacture products and provide discretionary services directly to the&#13;consumer, and the success of these companies is tied closely to the performance of the overall domestic and international economy,&#13;interest rates, competition and consumer confidence.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0 0pt 0.5in; text-align: justify"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0 0pt 0.5in; text-align: justify"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Consumer Staples Sector&#13;Risk&lt;/i&gt;. Companies in the consumer staples sector are subject to government regulation affecting the permissibility of using&#13;various food additives and production methods, which regulations could affect company profitability. Tobacco companies may be&#13;adversely affected by the adoption of proposed legislation and/or by litigation. Also, the success of food and soft drinks may&#13;be strongly affected by fads, marketing campaigns and other factors affecting supply and demand.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0 0pt 0.5in; text-align: justify"&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0 0pt 0.5in; text-align: justify"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Health Care Sector Risk&lt;/i&gt;.&#13;The health care sector may be affected by government regulations and government healthcare programs, increases or decreases in&#13;the cost of medical products and services and product liability claims, among other factors. Many health care companies are heavily&#13;dependent on patent protection, and the expiration of a patent may adversely affect their profitability. Health care companies&#13;are subject to competitive forces that may result in price discounting, and may be thinly capitalized and susceptible to product&#13;obsolescence.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0 0pt 0.5in; text-align: justify"&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0 0pt 0.5in; text-align: justify"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Information Technology&#13;Sector Risk&lt;/i&gt;. Information technology companies may also be smaller and less experienced companies, with limited product lines,&#13;markets or financial resources and fewer experienced management or marketing personnel. Information technology company stocks,&#13;especially those which are Internet related, have experienced extreme price and volume fluctuations that are often unrelated to&#13;their operating performance.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;&lt;font&gt;&lt;i&gt;Trading&#13;Risk&lt;/i&gt;. Shares of the Fund may trade on NYSE Arca, Inc. (the "Exchange") above or below their NAV. The NAV of shares&#13;of the Fund will fluctuate with changes in the market value of the Fund's holdings. In addition, although the Fund's&#13;shares are currently listed on the Exchange, there can be no assurance that an active trading market for shares will develop or&#13;be maintained. Trading in Fund shares may be halted due to market conditions or for reasons that, in the view of the Exchange,&#13;make trading in shares of the Fund inadvisable.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</RiskNarrativeTextBlock>
  <BarChartAndPerformanceTableHeading contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24_custom_S000067182Member">Performance Information</BarChartAndPerformanceTableHeading>
  <PerformanceNarrativeTextBlock contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24_custom_S000067182Member">&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;The Fund is new and therefore has no performance&#13;history. Once the Fund has completed a full calendar year of operations, a bar chart and table will be included that will provide&#13;some indication of the risks of investing in the Fund by comparing the Fund's return to a broad measure of market performance.&lt;/p&gt;</PerformanceNarrativeTextBlock>
  <RiskNotInsuredDepositoryInstitution contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24_custom_S000067182Member">An investment in the Fund is not a bank deposit and is not insured or guaranteed by the FDIC or any government agency.</RiskNotInsuredDepositoryInstitution>
  <RiskLoseMoney contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24_custom_S000067182Member">As with all funds, a shareholder is subject to the risk that his or her investment could lose money.</RiskLoseMoney>
  <ExpenseExchangeTradedFundCommissions contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24_custom_S000067182Member">This table and the Example below do not include the brokerage commissions that investors may pay on their purchases and sales of shares.</ExpenseExchangeTradedFundCommissions>
  <ManagementFeesOverAssets contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24_custom_S000067182Member_custom_C000216128Member" unitRef="Ratio" decimals="INF">0.0075</ManagementFeesOverAssets>
  <DistributionAndService12b1FeesOverAssets contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24_custom_S000067182Member_custom_C000216128Member" unitRef="Ratio" decimals="INF">0.0000</DistributionAndService12b1FeesOverAssets>
  <OtherExpensesOverAssets contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24_custom_S000067182Member_custom_C000216128Member" unitRef="Ratio" id="Foot-00-0" decimals="INF">0.0000</OtherExpensesOverAssets>
  <ExpensesOverAssets contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24_custom_S000067182Member_custom_C000216128Member" unitRef="Ratio" decimals="INF">0.0075</ExpensesOverAssets>
  <ExpenseExampleYear01 contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24_custom_S000067182Member_custom_C000216128Member" unitRef="USD" decimals="0">77</ExpenseExampleYear01>
  <ExpenseExampleYear03 contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24_custom_S000067182Member_custom_C000216128Member" unitRef="USD" decimals="0">240</ExpenseExampleYear03>
  <AnnualFundOperatingExpensesTableTextBlock contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24_custom_S000067182Member">&lt;div style="display: none"&gt;~ http://qraftaietf.com/role/OperatingExpensesData column period compact * column dei_LegalEntityAxis compact ck0001547950_S000067182Member column rr_ProspectusShareClassAxis compact * row primary compact * ~&lt;/div&gt;</AnnualFundOperatingExpensesTableTextBlock>
  <ExpenseExampleWithRedemptionTableTextBlock contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24_custom_S000067182Member">&lt;div style="display: none"&gt;~ http://qraftaietf.com/role/ExpenseExample column period compact * column dei_LegalEntityAxis compact ck0001547950_S000067182Member column rr_ProspectusShareClassAxis compact * row primary compact * ~&lt;/div&gt;</ExpenseExampleWithRedemptionTableTextBlock>
  <StrategyNarrativeTextBlock contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24_custom_S000067182Member">&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0"&gt;&lt;font style="font: normal 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;&lt;font style="font: normal 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif"&gt;The&#13;Fund is an actively-managed exchange-traded fund ("ETF") that seeks to achieve its investment objective by investing at least&#13;80% of its net assets, plus the amounts of any borrowings for investment purposes, in dividend paying securities of U.S.-listed&#13;companies. In addition, the Fund will generally invest in U.S.-liste compdanies having a market capitalization in excess of $4&#13;billion at the time of purchase (the "Universe"). The Fund will invest in equity securities (i.e., common stock) of such companies.&#13;The Fund's adviser, Exchange Traded Concepts, LLC (the "Adviser"), uses an investment process based on a proprietary artificial&#13;intelligence security selection process that extracts patterns from analyzing data, as discussed below, developed by QRAFT Technologies,&#13;Inc. ("Qraft"). Qraft is a South Korea-based provider of artificial intelligence investment systems and currently offers services&#13;to various financial institutions in Korea. The Adviser has licensed Qraft's proprietary artificial intelligence security selection&#13;process for the management of the Fund.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;&lt;font style="font: normal 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif"&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;&lt;font style="font: normal 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif"&gt;In&#13;pursuing the Fund's investment objective, the Adviser consults a database generated by Qraft's AI Quantitative Investment System&#13;("AQUA"). Qraft created AQUA to automatically evaluate and filter data according to parameters supporting a particular investment&#13;thesis. For the Fund's database, AQUA applies its artificial intelligence to develop a portfolio of investments based on the theory&#13;that short-term price return is potentially a better indicator of a higher dividend yield of a stock than the traditional method&#13;of high-dividend stock picking. AQUA filters the securities in the Universe into an investment pool of 150 stocks using a proprietary&#13;dividend factor scoring formula based on dividend and quality factors including but not limited to dividend yield and dividend&#13;growth. AQUA then estimates each stock's relative superiority of price appreciation (i.e., increase in stock price) over the rest&#13;of the pool for the next three month investment period using deep learning technologies (i.e., exposure to and processing of large&#13;amounts of data) and the distribution of each stock's relative superiority of price appreciation for the same period using Bayesian&#13;neural networks that estimate the uncertainty of its forecast, and selects the top 100 stocks based on the average of the distribution&#13;of each stock's relative superiority of price appreciation for inclusion in the database. The stocks included in the database&#13;are weighted based on their market capitalization.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;&lt;font style="font: normal 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif"&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;&lt;font style="font: normal 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif"&gt;The&#13;Fund expects to hold 100 companies in its portfolio. While it is anticipated that the Adviser will purchase and sell securities&#13;based on recommendations by the AQUA database described above, the Adviser has full discretion over investment decisions for the&#13;Fund. Therefore, the Adviser has full decision-making power not only if it identifies a potential technical issue or error with&#13;the AQUA database, but also if it believes that the recommended portfolio does not further the Fund's investment objective or&#13;fails to take into account company events such as corporate actions, mergers and spin-offs. Additionally, the Adviser has discretion&#13;over the amount of cash maintained in the Fund's portfolio and the reinvestment of dividends in the Fund's portfolio, subject&#13;to the Fund's distribution requirements as a regulated investment company for federal income tax purposes. See "Federal Income&#13;Taxes" in the Fund's Statement of Additional Information ("SAI") for a more complete discussion. Notwithstanding the foregoing,&#13;the Fund limits the weighting of a single company to 10% and no more than 40% of the Fund's assets may be invested in securities&#13;with a more than 5% weighting in the Fund's portfolio. Due to frequency of the rebalancing of the AQUA database, the Adviser expects&#13;that the Fund will frequently purchase and sell shares of securities.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;&lt;font style="font: normal 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif"&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;&#13;&lt;p style="font: 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif; margin: 0pt 0; text-align: justify"&gt;&lt;font style="font: normal 10pt Times New Roman, Times, Serif"&gt;While&#13;investing in a particular market sector is not a strategy of the Fund, its portfolio may be significantly invested in one or more&#13;sectors as a result of the security selection decisions made pursuant to its strategy. Currently, the Fund expects to invest a&#13;significant portion of its assets in the securities of companies in the consumer staples, consumer discretionary, health care,&#13;information technology, and communication services sectors, although this may change from time to time. The Fund is non-diversified&#13;and may invest a greater percentage of its assets in a particular issuer than a diversified fund.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</StrategyNarrativeTextBlock>
  <OtherExpensesNewFundBasedOnEstimates contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24_custom_S000067182Member">Other Expenses are based on estimated amounts for the current fiscal year.</OtherExpensesNewFundBasedOnEstimates>
  <RiskNondiversifiedStatus contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24_custom_S000067182Member">The Fund is a non-diversified investment company under the Investment Company Act of 1940 (the "1940 Act"), meaning that, as compared to a diversified fund, it can invest a greater percentage of its assets in securities issued by or representing a small number of issuers. As a result, the performance of these issuers can have a substantial impact on the Fund's performance.</RiskNondiversifiedStatus>
  <PerformanceOneYearOrLess contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24_custom_S000067182Member">Once the Fund has completed a full calendar year of operations, a bar chart and table will be included that will provide some indication of the risks of investing in the Fund by comparing the Fund's return to a broad measure of market performance.</PerformanceOneYearOrLess>
  <StrategyPortfolioConcentration contextRef="AsOf2020-02-24_custom_S000067182Member">The Fund is an actively-managed exchange-traded fund ("ETF") that seeks to achieve its investment objective by investing at least 80% of its net assets, plus the amounts of any borrowings for investment purposes, in dividend paying securities of U.S.-listed companies. While investing in a particular market sector is not a strategy of the Fund, its portfolio may be significantly invested in one or more sectors as a result of the security selection decisions made pursuant to its strategy. Currently, the Fund expects to invest a significant portion of its assets in the securities of companies in the consumer staples, consumer discretionary, health care, information technology, and communication services sectors, although this may change from time to time.</StrategyPortfolioConcentration>
  <footnoteLink type="extended" role="http://www.xbrl.org/2003/role/link">
    <loc type="locator" href="#Foot-00-0" label="Foot-00_loc"/>
    <footnoteArc type="arc" arcrole="http://www.xbrl.org/2003/arcrole/fact-footnote" from="Foot-00_loc" to="Footnote-01" order="1"/>
    <footnote type="resource" role="http://www.xbrl.org/2003/role/footnote" label="Footnote-01" lang="en-US">Other Expenses are based on estimated amounts for the current fiscal year.</footnote>
  </footnoteLink>
</xbrl>
