<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<!--XBRL document created by Donnelley Financial Solutions IM Processor 9.1.2.0 using Fujitsu Interstage XWand-->
<xbrl xmlns:ftetfiv="http://www.ftportfolios.com/20181231" xmlns:dei="http://xbrl.sec.gov/dei/2018-01-31" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:rr="http://xbrl.sec.gov/rr/2018-01-31" xmlns:link="http://www.xbrl.org/2003/linkbase" xmlns:iso4217="http://www.xbrl.org/2003/iso4217" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xbrldi="http://xbrl.org/2006/xbrldi" xmlns="http://www.xbrl.org/2003/instance">
  <link:schemaRef xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="ftetfiv-20181231.xsd" />
  <context id="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018">
    <entity>
      <identifier scheme="http://www.sec.gov/CIK">0001517936</identifier>
    </entity>
    <period>
      <startDate>2018-12-31</startDate>
      <endDate>2018-12-31</endDate>
    </period>
  </context>
  <context id="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_Member">
    <entity>
      <identifier scheme="http://www.sec.gov/CIK">0001517936</identifier>
      <segment>
        <xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="dei:LegalEntityAxis">ftetfiv:S000034146Member</xbrldi:explicitMember>
      </segment>
    </entity>
    <period>
      <startDate>2018-12-31</startDate>
      <endDate>2018-12-31</endDate>
    </period>
  </context>
  <context id="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberC000105232_Member">
    <entity>
      <identifier scheme="http://www.sec.gov/CIK">0001517936</identifier>
      <segment>
        <xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="dei:LegalEntityAxis">ftetfiv:S000034146Member</xbrldi:explicitMember>
        <xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="rr:ProspectusShareClassAxis">ftetfiv:C000105232Member</xbrldi:explicitMember>
      </segment>
    </entity>
    <period>
      <startDate>2018-12-31</startDate>
      <endDate>2018-12-31</endDate>
    </period>
  </context>
  <context id="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberC000105232_MemberAftertaxondistributions_Member">
    <entity>
      <identifier scheme="http://www.sec.gov/CIK">0001517936</identifier>
      <segment>
        <xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="dei:LegalEntityAxis">ftetfiv:S000034146Member</xbrldi:explicitMember>
        <xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="rr:ProspectusShareClassAxis">ftetfiv:C000105232Member</xbrldi:explicitMember>
        <xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="rr:PerformanceMeasureAxis">ftetfiv:AftertaxondistributionsMember</xbrldi:explicitMember>
      </segment>
    </entity>
    <period>
      <startDate>2018-12-31</startDate>
      <endDate>2018-12-31</endDate>
    </period>
  </context>
  <context id="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberC000105232_MemberAftertaxondistributionsandsaleoffundshares_Member">
    <entity>
      <identifier scheme="http://www.sec.gov/CIK">0001517936</identifier>
      <segment>
        <xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="dei:LegalEntityAxis">ftetfiv:S000034146Member</xbrldi:explicitMember>
        <xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="rr:ProspectusShareClassAxis">ftetfiv:C000105232Member</xbrldi:explicitMember>
        <xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="rr:PerformanceMeasureAxis">ftetfiv:AftertaxondistributionsandsaleoffundsharesMember</xbrldi:explicitMember>
      </segment>
    </entity>
    <period>
      <startDate>2018-12-31</startDate>
      <endDate>2018-12-31</endDate>
    </period>
  </context>
  <context id="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberMarkitiBoxxUSDLiquidLeveragedLoanIndex_Member">
    <entity>
      <identifier scheme="http://www.sec.gov/CIK">0001517936</identifier>
      <segment>
        <xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="dei:LegalEntityAxis">ftetfiv:S000034146Member</xbrldi:explicitMember>
        <xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="rr:PerformanceMeasureAxis">ftetfiv:MarkitiBoxxUSDLiquidLeveragedLoanIndexMember</xbrldi:explicitMember>
      </segment>
    </entity>
    <period>
      <startDate>2018-12-31</startDate>
      <endDate>2018-12-31</endDate>
    </period>
  </context>
  <context id="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberSPLSTALeveragedLoan100Index_Member">
    <entity>
      <identifier scheme="http://www.sec.gov/CIK">0001517936</identifier>
      <segment>
        <xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="dei:LegalEntityAxis">ftetfiv:S000034146Member</xbrldi:explicitMember>
        <xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="rr:PerformanceMeasureAxis">ftetfiv:SPLSTALeveragedLoan100IndexMember</xbrldi:explicitMember>
      </segment>
    </entity>
    <period>
      <startDate>2018-12-31</startDate>
      <endDate>2018-12-31</endDate>
    </period>
  </context>
  <unit id="pure">
    <measure>pure</measure>
  </unit>
  <unit id="USD">
    <measure>iso4217:USD</measure>
  </unit>
  <rr:ProspectusDate contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018">2018-12-31</rr:ProspectusDate>
  <dei:DocumentPeriodEndDate contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018">2018-12-31</dei:DocumentPeriodEndDate>
  <dei:EntityRegistrantName contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018">First Trust Exchange-Traded Fund IV</dei:EntityRegistrantName>
  <dei:EntityCentralIndexKey contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018">0001517936</dei:EntityCentralIndexKey>
  <dei:AmendmentFlag contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018">false</dei:AmendmentFlag>
  <dei:DocumentCreationDate contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018">2018-12-31</dei:DocumentCreationDate>
  <dei:DocumentEffectiveDate contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018">2018-12-31</dei:DocumentEffectiveDate>
  <dei:EntityInvCompanyType contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018">N-1A</dei:EntityInvCompanyType>
  <dei:DocumentType contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018">485BPOS</dei:DocumentType>
  <rr:RiskReturnHeading contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_Member">&lt;p&gt;Summary Information&lt;/p&gt;</rr:RiskReturnHeading>
  <rr:ObjectiveHeading contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_Member">&lt;p&gt;Investment Objectives&lt;/p&gt;</rr:ObjectiveHeading>
  <rr:ObjectivePrimaryTextBlock contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_Member">&lt;p&gt;The First Trust Senior Loan Fund&amp;#39;s (the "&lt;i&gt;Fund&lt;/i&gt;") primary investment objective is to provide high current income. The Fund&amp;#39;s secondary investment objective is the preservation of capital.&lt;/p&gt;</rr:ObjectivePrimaryTextBlock>
  <rr:ExpenseHeading contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_Member">&lt;p&gt;Fees and Expenses of the Fund&lt;/p&gt;</rr:ExpenseHeading>
  <rr:ExpenseNarrativeTextBlock contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_Member">&lt;p&gt;The following table describes the fees and expenses you may pay if you buy and hold shares of the Fund. Investors purchasing and selling shares may be subject to costs (including customary brokerage commissions) charged by their broker, which are not reflected in the table below.&lt;/p&gt;</rr:ExpenseNarrativeTextBlock>
  <rr:ShareholderFeesCaption contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_Member">&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;Shareholder Fees&lt;/b&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;(fees paid directly from your investment)&lt;/p&gt;</rr:ShareholderFeesCaption>
  <rr:OperatingExpensesCaption contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_Member">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;Annual Fund Operating Expenses&lt;/b&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;(expenses that you pay each year as a percentage of the value of your investment)&lt;/p&gt;</rr:OperatingExpensesCaption>
  <rr:ExpenseExampleHeading contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_Member">&lt;p&gt;Example&lt;/p&gt;</rr:ExpenseExampleHeading>
  <rr:ExpenseExampleNoRedemptionNarrativeTextBlock contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_Member">&lt;p&gt;The example below is intended to help you compare the cost of investing in the Fund with the cost of investing in other funds. This example does not take into account customary brokerage commissions that you pay when purchasing or selling shares of the Fund in the secondary market.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The example assumes that you invest $10,000 in the Fund for the time periods indicated. The example also assumes that your investment has a 5% return each year and that the Fund&amp;#39;s operating expenses remain at current levels. Although your actual costs may be higher or lower, based on these assumptions your costs would be:&lt;/p&gt;</rr:ExpenseExampleNoRedemptionNarrativeTextBlock>
  <rr:PortfolioTurnoverHeading contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_Member">&lt;p&gt;Portfolio Turnover&lt;/p&gt;</rr:PortfolioTurnoverHeading>
  <rr:PortfolioTurnoverTextBlock contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_Member">&lt;p&gt;The Fund pays transaction costs, such as commissions, when it buys and sells securities (or "turns over" its portfolio). A higher portfolio turnover rate may indicate higher transaction costs and may result in higher taxes when Fund shares are held in a taxable account. These costs, which are not reflected in annual fund operating expenses or in the example, affect the Fund&amp;#39;s performance. During the most recent fiscal year, the Fund&amp;#39;s portfolio turnover rate was 110% of the average value of its portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;</rr:PortfolioTurnoverTextBlock>
  <rr:StrategyHeading contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_Member">&lt;p&gt;Principal Investment Strategies&lt;/p&gt;</rr:StrategyHeading>
  <rr:StrategyNarrativeTextBlock contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_Member">&lt;p&gt;Under normal market conditions, the Fund seeks to outperform each of the Primary Index and Secondary Index (as defined below) by investing at least 80% of its net assets (including investment borrowings) in first lien senior floating rate bank loans (&lt;i&gt;"Senior Loans"&lt;/i&gt;). The S&amp;amp;P/LSTA U.S. Leveraged Loan 100 Index (the &lt;i&gt;"Primary Index"&lt;/i&gt;) is a market value-weighted index designed to measure the performance of the largest segment of the U.S. syndicated leveraged loan market. The Primary Index consists of 100 loan facilities drawn from a larger benchmark, the S&amp;amp;P/LSTA Leveraged Loan Index. The Markit iBoxx USD Liquid Leveraged Loan Index (the &lt;i&gt;"Secondary Index"&lt;/i&gt;) selects the 100 most liquid Senior Loans in the market. The Fund does not seek to track either the Primary or Secondary Index, but rather seeks to outperform each of the indices. It is anticipated that the Fund, in accordance with its principal investment strategy, will invest approximately 50% to 75% of its net assets in Senior Loans that are eligible for inclusion in and meet the liquidity thresholds of the Primary and/or the Secondary Indices at the time of investment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Senior Loan is an advance or commitment of funds made by one or more banks or similar financial institutions to one or more corporations, partnerships or other business entities and typically pays interest at a floating or adjusting rate that is determined periodically at a designated premium above a base lending rate, most commonly the London Interbank Offered Rate (&lt;i&gt;"LIBOR"&lt;/i&gt;). A Senior Loan is considered senior to all other unsecured claims against the borrower, senior to or equal with all other secured claims, meaning that in the event of a bankruptcy of the borrower the Senior Loan, together with other first lien claims, is entitled to be the first to be repaid out of proceeds of the assets securing the loans, before other existing unsecured claims or interests receive repayment. However, in bankruptcy proceedings, there may be other claims, such as taxes or additional advances that take precedence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Fund may invest significantly in "covenant-lite" loans, which are loans issued with fewer restrictions on collateral, payment terms and level of income. Traditional loans generally have protective covenants built into the contract to protect the lender, including financial maintenance tests that measure the debt-service capabilities of the borrower; however, covenant-lite loans lack many of these lender protection provisions. Covenant-lite loans carry more risk than traditional loans and allow borrowers to engage in activities that would be difficult or impossible under a traditional loan agreement. The lack of traditional lender protection provisions contained in covenant-lite loans may impact recovery values and/or trading levels in the future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Fund invests in Senior Loans made predominantly to businesses operating in North America, but may also invest in Senior Loans made to businesses operating outside of North America. The Fund may invest in Senior Loans directly, either from the borrower as part of a primary issuance or in the secondary market through assignments of portions of Senior Loans from third parties, or participations in Senior Loans, which are contractual relationships with an existing lender in a loan facility whereby the Fund purchases the right to receive principal and interest payments on a loan but the existing lender remains the record holder of the loan. The Senior Loans included in the Fund&amp;#39;s portfolio often maintain a duration of less than 90 days; however, the inclusion of LIBOR floors on certain Senior Loans or other factors may cause interest rate duration to be longer than 90 days.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When identifying prospective investment opportunities in Senior Loans, First Trust Advisors L.P., the Fund&amp;#39;s investment advisor, currently intends to invest primarily in Senior Loans that are below investment grade quality at the time of investment, and relies on fundamental credit analysis in an effort to attempt to minimize the loss of the Fund&amp;#39;s capital and to select assets that provide attractive relative value. Securities rated below investment grade, commonly referred to as &lt;i&gt;"junk"&lt;/i&gt; or &lt;i&gt;"high yield"&lt;/i&gt; securities, include securities that are rated Ba1/BB+/BB+ or below by Moody&amp;#39;s Investors Service, Inc. (&lt;i&gt;"Moody&amp;#39;s"&lt;/i&gt;), Fitch Inc., or Standard &amp;amp; Poor&amp;#39;s, Inc. (&lt;i&gt;"S&amp;amp;P"&lt;/i&gt;), respectively. The Fund may invest in securities of any rating. The Fund may also invest in unrated securities deemed by the investment advisor to be of comparable quality to those securities rated below investment grade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Fund may also invest up to 20% of its net assets in (1) non-Senior Loan debt securities, which may be fixed-rate or floating-rate income-producing securities (including, without limitation, U.S. government debt securities and corporate debt securities, which may include convertible bonds), (2) warrants, U.S. and non-U.S. equity and equity-like positions and interests and other securities issued by or with respect to a borrower or its affiliates, and/or (3) securities of other investment companies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition, the Fund may invest up to 15% of its net assets in Senior Loans and/or other floating rate loans that are distressed or in default.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Fund&amp;#39;s investment advisor combines a fundamental credit selection process with relative value analysis and top-down macroeconomic perspectives when selecting investment opportunities. The Fund&amp;#39;s investment advisor believes that an evolving investment environment offers varying degrees of investment risk opportunities in the bank loan, high yield and other fixed income instrument markets. To capitalize on attractive investments and effectively manage potential risk, the Fund&amp;#39;s investment advisor believes that the combination of thorough and continuous credit analysis, market evaluation, diversification and the ability to reallocate investments is critical to achieving higher risk-adjusted returns.&lt;/p&gt;</rr:StrategyNarrativeTextBlock>
  <rr:RiskHeading contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_Member">&lt;p&gt;Principal Risks&lt;/p&gt;</rr:RiskHeading>
  <rr:RiskNarrativeTextBlock contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_Member">&lt;p&gt;You could lose money by investing in the Fund. An investment in the Fund is not a deposit of a bank and is not insured or guaranteed by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation or any other governmental agency. There can be no assurance that the Fund&amp;#39;s investment objectives will be achieved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;AUTHORIZED PARTICIPANT CONCENTRATION RISK.&lt;/b&gt; Only an authorized participant may engage in creation or redemption transactions directly with the Fund. A limited number of institutions act as authorized participants for the Fund. To the extent that these institutions exit the business or are unable to proceed with creation and/or redemption orders and no other authorized participant steps forward to create or redeem, the Fund&amp;#39;s shares may trade at a premium or discount to the Fund&amp;#39;s net asset value and possibly face delisting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;BANK LOANS RISK.&lt;/b&gt;  Investments in bank loans are subject to the same risks as investments in other types of debt securities, including credit risk, interest rate risk, liquidity risk and valuation risk that may be heightened because of the limited public information available regarding bank loans and because loan borrowers may be leveraged and tend to be more adversely affected by changes in market or economic conditions. If the Fund holds a bank loan through another financial institution or relies on a financial institution to administer the loan, its receipt of principal and interest on the loan may be subject to the credit risk of that financial institution. It is possible that any collateral securing a loan may be insufficient or unavailable to the Fund, and that the Fund&amp;#39;s rights to collateral may be limited by bankruptcy or insolvency laws. Additionally, there is no central clearinghouse for loan trades and the loan market has not established enforceable settlement standards or remedies for failure to settle. As such, the secondary market for bank loans may be subject to irregular trading activity, wide bid/ask spreads and extended trade settlement periods (in some cases longer than 7 days) which may cause the Fund to be unable to realize the full value of its investment. In addition, bank loans are generally not registered with the Securities Exchange Commission under the Securities Act of 1933, as amended, and may not be considered "securities," and the Fund may not be entitled to rely on the anti-fraud protections of the federal securities laws.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;CALL RISK.&lt;/b&gt;  Some debt securities may be redeemed, or "called," at the option of the issuer before their stated maturity date. In general, an issuer will call its debt securities if they can be refinanced by issuing new debt securities which bear a lower interest rate. The Fund is subject to the possibility that during periods of falling interest rates an issuer will call its high yielding debt securities. The Fund would then be forced to invest the proceeds at lower interest rates, likely resulting in a decline in the Fund&amp;#39;s income.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;CASH TRANSACTIONS RISK.&lt;/b&gt; The Fund will effect some or all&amp;#160;of its creations and redemptions for cash rather than in-kind. As a result, an investment in the Fund may be less tax-efficient than an investment in an ETF that effects all of its creations and redemptions in-kind. Because the Fund may effect redemptions for cash, it may be required to sell portfolio securities in order to obtain the cash needed to distribute redemption proceeds. A sale of shares may result in capital gains or losses and may also result in higher brokerage costs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;CONVERTIBLE SECURITIES RISK.&lt;/b&gt;  A convertible security has characteristics of both equity and debt securities and, as a result, is exposed to risks that are typically associated with both types of securities.  The value of convertible securities may rise and fall with the market value of the underlying stock or, like a debt security, vary with changes in interest rates and the credit quality of the issuer. A convertible security tends to perform more like a stock when the underlying stock price is high relative to the conversion price and more like a debt security when the underlying stock price is low relative to the conversion price.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;COVENANT-LITE LOAN RISK.&lt;/b&gt; There may be instances in which the Fund invests in covenant-lite loans. Covenant-lite loans contain fewer maintenance covenants, or no maintenance covenants at all, than traditional loans and may not include terms that allow the lender to monitor the financial performance of the borrower and declare a default if certain criteria are breached. This may hinder the Fund&amp;#39;s ability to reprice credit risk associated with the borrower and reduce the Fund&amp;#39;s ability to restructure a problematic loan and mitigate potential loss. As a result, the Fund&amp;#39;s exposure to losses on such investments is increased, especially during a downturn in the credit cycle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;CREDIT RISK.&lt;/b&gt;  An issuer or other obligated party of a debt security may be unable or unwilling to make dividend, interest and/or principal payments when due.  In addition, the value of a debt security may decline because of concerns about the issuer&amp;#39;s ability or unwillingness to make such payments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;CURRENCY RISK.&lt;/b&gt;  Changes in currency exchange rates affect the value of investments denominated in a foreign currency, and therefore the value of such investments in the Fund&amp;#39;s portfolio. The Fund&amp;#39;s net asset value could decline if a currency to which the Fund has exposure depreciates against the U.S. dollar or if there are delays or limits on repatriation of such currency. Currency exchange rates can be very volatile and can change quickly and unpredictably. As a result, the value of an investment in the Fund may change quickly and without warning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;CYBER SECURITY RISK.&lt;/b&gt; The Fund is susceptible to operational risks through breaches in cyber security. A breach in cyber security refers to both intentional and unintentional events that may cause the Fund to lose proprietary information, suffer data corruption or lose operational capacity. Such events could cause the Fund to incur regulatory penalties, reputational damage, additional compliance costs associated with corrective measures and/or financial loss. Cyber security breaches may involve unauthorized access to the Fund&amp;#39;s digital information systems through "hacking" or malicious software coding but may also result from outside attacks such as denial-of-service attacks through efforts to make network services unavailable to intended users. In addition, cyber security breaches of the securities issuers or the Fund&amp;#39;s third-party service providers, such as its administrator, transfer agent, custodian, or sub-advisor, as applicable, or issuers in which the Fund invests, can also subject the Fund to many of the same risks associated with direct cyber security breaches. Although the Fund has established risk management systems designed to reduce the risks associated with cyber security, there is no guarantee that such efforts will succeed, especially because the Fund does not directly control the cyber security systems of issuers or third-party service providers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;DEFAULTED SECURITIES RISK.&lt;/b&gt; Defaulted securities pose a greater risk that principal will not be repaid than non-defaulted securities. The reorganization or liquidation of an issuer of a defaulted security may result in the Fund losing its entire investment or being required to accept cash or securities with a value less than its original investment. It may also be difficult to obtain complete and accurate information regarding the true financial condition of the issuer of a defaulted security. Defaulted securities and any securities received in an exchange for such securities may be subject to restrictions on resale.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;DISTRESSED SECURITIES RISK.&lt;/b&gt;  Distressed debt securities are speculative and involve substantial risks in addition to the risks of investing in high-yield securities that are not in default. Generally, the Fund will not receive interest payments from the distressed securities it holds, and there is a substantial risk that the principal will not be repaid. In any reorganization or liquidation proceeding related to a distressed debt security, the Fund may lose its entire investment in the security.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;EXTENSION RISK.&lt;/b&gt;  Extension risk is the risk that, when interest rates rise, certain obligations will be paid off by the issuer (or other obligated party) more slowly than anticipated, causing the value of these debt securities to fall. Rising interest rates tend to extend the duration of debt securities, making their market value more sensitive to changes in interest rates. The value of longer-term debt securities generally changes more in response to changes in interest rates than shorter-term debt securities. As a result, in a period of rising interest rates, securities may exhibit additional volatility and may lose value.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;HIGH YIELD SECURITIES RISK.&lt;/b&gt;  High yield securities, or "junk" bonds, are subject to greater market fluctuations, are less liquid and provide a greater risk of loss than investment grade securities, and therefore, are considered to be highly speculative. In general, high yield securities may have a greater risk of default than other types of securities and could cause income and principal losses for the Fund.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;INCOME RISK.&lt;/b&gt;  The Fund&amp;#39;s income may decline when interest rates fall or if there are defaults in its portfolio. This decline can occur because the Fund may subsequently invest in lower-yielding securities as debt securities in its portfolio mature, are near maturity or are called, or the Fund otherwise needs to purchase additional debt securities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;INTEREST RATE RISK.&lt;/b&gt;  Interest rate risk is the risk that the value of the debt securities in the Fund&amp;#39;s portfolio will decline because of rising market interest rates. Interest rate risk is generally lower for shorter term debt securities and higher for longer-term debt securities. The Fund may be subject to a greater risk of rising interest rates than would normally be the case due to the current period of historically low rates and the effect of potential government fiscal policy initiatives and resulting market reaction to those initiatives.  Duration is a reasonably accurate measure of a debt security&amp;#39;s price sensitivity to changes in interest rates and a common measure of interest rate risk. Duration measures a debt security&amp;#39;s expected life on a present value basis, taking into account the debt security&amp;#39;s yield, interest payments and final maturity. In general, duration represents the expected percentage change in the value of a security for an immediate 1% change in interest rates. For example, the price of a debt security with a three-year duration would be expected to drop by approximately 3% in response to a 1% increase in interest rates. Therefore, prices of debt securities with shorter durations tend to be less sensitive to interest rate changes than debt securities with longer durations. As the value of a debt security changes over time, so will its duration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;LIQUIDITY RISK.&lt;/b&gt; The Fund investments may be subject to restrictions on resale, trade over-the-counter or in limited volume, or lack an active trading market. Accordingly, the Fund may not be able to sell or close out of such investments at favorable times or prices (or at all), or at the prices approximating those at which the Fund currently values them.  Illiquid securities may trade at a discount from comparable, more liquid investments and may be subject to wide fluctuations in market value.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;MANAGEMENT RISK.&lt;/b&gt; The Fund is subject to management risk because it is an actively managed portfolio. In managing the Fund&amp;#39;s investment portfolio, the portfolio managers will apply investment techniques and risk analyses that may not produce the desired result. There can be no guarantee that the Fund will meet its investment objectives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;MARKET MAKER RISK.&lt;/b&gt; The Fund faces numerous market trading risks, including the potential lack of an active market for Fund shares due to a limited number of market markers.  Decisions by market makers or authorized participants to reduce their role or step away from these activities in times of market stress could inhibit the effectiveness of the arbitrage process in maintaining the relationship between the underlying values of the Fund&amp;#39;s portfolio securities and the Fund&amp;#39;s market price. The Fund may rely on a small number of third-party market makers to provide a market for the purchase and sale of shares. Any trading halt or other problem relating to the trading activity of these market makers could result in a dramatic change in the spread between the Fund&amp;#39;s net asset value and the price at which the Fund&amp;#39;s shares are trading on the Exchange, which could result in a decrease in value of the Fund&amp;#39;s shares. This reduced effectiveness could result in Fund shares trading at a discount to net asset value and also in greater than normal intraday bid-ask spreads for Fund shares.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;MARKET RISK.&lt;/b&gt; Market risk is the risk that a particular security, or shares of the Fund in general, may fall in value. Securities are subject to market fluctuations caused by such factors as economic, political, regulatory or market developments, changes in interest rates and perceived trends in securities prices. Shares of the Fund could decline in value or underperform other investments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;NON-U.S. SECURITIES RISK.&lt;/b&gt;  Non-U.S. securities are subject to higher volatility than securities of domestic issuers due to possible adverse political, social or economic developments, restrictions on foreign investment or exchange of securities, lack of liquidity, currency exchange rates, excessive taxation, government seizure of assets, different legal or accounting standards, and less government supervision and regulation of securities exchanges in foreign countries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;OTHER DEBT SECURITIES RISK.&lt;/b&gt; Secured loans that are not first lien loans, unsecured loans and other debt securities are subject to many of the same risks that affect Senior Loans; however they are often unsecured and/or lower in the issuer&amp;#39;s capital structure than Senior Loans, and thus may be exposed to greater risk of default and lower recoveries in the event of a default. This risk can be further heightened in the case of below investment grade instruments. Additionally, most fixed income securities are fixed-rate and thus are generally more susceptible than floating rate loans to price volatility related to changes in prevailing interest rates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;PORTFOLIO TURNOVER RISK.&lt;/b&gt; High portfolio turnover may result in the Fund paying higher levels of transaction costs and may generate greater tax liabilities for shareholders. Portfolio turnover risk may cause the Fund&amp;#39;s performance to be less than expected.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;PREMIUM/DISCOUNT RISK.&lt;/b&gt; The market price of the Fund&amp;#39;s shares will generally fluctuate in accordance with changes in the Fund&amp;#39;s net asset value as well as the relative supply of and demand for shares on the Exchange. The Fund&amp;#39;s investment advisor cannot predict whether shares will trade below, at or above their net asset value because the shares trade on the Exchange at market prices and not at net asset value. Price differences may be due, in large part, to the fact that supply and demand forces at work in the secondary trading market for shares will be closely related, but not identical, to the same forces influencing the prices of the holdings of the Fund trading individually or in the aggregate at any point in time. However, given that shares can only be purchased and redeemed in Creation Units, and only to and from broker-dealers and large institutional investors that have entered into participation agreements (unlike shares of closed-end funds, which frequently trade at appreciable discounts from, and sometimes at premiums to, their net asset value), the Fund&amp;#39;s investment advisor believes that large discounts or premiums to the net asset value of shares should not be sustained.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;PREPAYMENT RISK.&lt;/b&gt;  Prepayment risk is the risk that the issuer of a debt security will repay principal prior to the scheduled maturity date. Debt securities allowing prepayment may offer less potential for gains during a period of declining interest rates, as the Fund may be required to reinvest the proceeds of any prepayment at lower interest rates. These factors may cause the value of an investment in the Fund to change.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;TRADING ISSUES RISK.&lt;/b&gt; Although the shares of the Fund are listed for trading on the Exchange, there can be no assurance that an active trading market for such shares will develop or be maintained. Trading in shares on the Exchange may be halted due to market conditions or for reasons that, in the view of the Exchange, make trading in shares inadvisable. In addition, trading in shares on the Exchange is subject to trading halts caused by extraordinary market volatility pursuant to the Exchange&amp;#39;s "circuit breaker" rules. Market makers are under no obligation to make a market in the Fund&amp;#39;s shares, and authorized participants are not obligated to submit purchase or redemption orders for Creation Units. In the event market makers cease making a market in the Fund&amp;#39;s shares or authorized participants stop submitting purchase or redemption orders for Creation Units, Fund shares may trade at a larger premium or discount to their net asset value. There can be no assurance that the requirements of the Exchange necessary to maintain the listing of the Fund will continue to be met or will remain unchanged. The Fund may have difficulty maintaining its listing on the Exchange in the event the Fund&amp;#39;s assets are small or the Fund does not have enough shareholders.&lt;/p&gt;</rr:RiskNarrativeTextBlock>
  <rr:BarChartAndPerformanceTableHeading contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_Member">&lt;p&gt;Annual Total Return&lt;/p&gt;</rr:BarChartAndPerformanceTableHeading>
  <rr:PerformanceNarrativeTextBlock contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_Member">&lt;p&gt;The bar chart and table below illustrate the annual calendar year returns of the Fund based on net asset value as well as the average annual Fund returns. The bar chart and table provide an indication of the risks of investing in the Fund by showing changes in the Fund&amp;#39;s performance from year-to-year and by showing how the Fund&amp;#39;s average annual total returns based on net asset value compared to those of two broad-based market indices.  See "Total Return Information" for additional performance information regarding the Fund. The Fund&amp;#39;s performance information is accessible on the Fund&amp;#39;s website at www.ftportfolios.com.&lt;/p&gt;</rr:PerformanceNarrativeTextBlock>
  <rr:BarChartHeading contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_Member">&lt;p&gt;First Trust Senior Loan Fund&lt;br /&gt;Calendar Year Total Returns as of 12/31 &lt;sup&gt;(1)&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</rr:BarChartHeading>
  <rr:BarChartFootnotesTextBlock contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_Member">(1)The Fund&amp;#39;s calendar year-to-date total return based on net asset value for the period 12/31/17 to 9/30/18 was 2.91%.</rr:BarChartFootnotesTextBlock>
  <rr:BarChartClosingTextBlock contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_Member">&lt;p&gt;During the periods shown in the chart above:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td valign="top" align="left"&gt;Best Quarter&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td valign="top" align="left" /&gt;
    &lt;td valign="top" align="left"&gt;Worst Quarter&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td valign="top" align="left" /&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td valign="top" align="left"&gt;2.17%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td valign="top" align="left"&gt;March 31, 2016&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td valign="top" align="left"&gt;-1.63%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td valign="top" align="left"&gt;December 31, 2015&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Fund&amp;#39;s past performance (before and after taxes) is not necessarily an indication of how the Fund will perform in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</rr:BarChartClosingTextBlock>
  <rr:PerformanceTableNarrativeTextBlock contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_Member">&lt;p&gt;Returns before taxes do not reflect the effects of any income or capital gains taxes. All after-tax returns are calculated using the historical highest individual federal marginal income tax rates and do not reflect the impact of any state or local tax. Returns after taxes on distributions reflect the taxed return on the payment of dividends and capital gains. Returns after taxes on distributions and sale of shares assume you sold your shares at period end, and, therefore, are also adjusted for any capital gains or losses incurred. Returns for the market indices do not include expenses, which are deducted from Fund returns, or taxes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your own actual after-tax returns will depend on your specific tax situation and may differ from what is shown here. After-tax returns are not relevant to investors who hold Fund shares in tax-deferred accounts such as individual retirement accounts (&lt;i&gt;IRAs&lt;/i&gt;) or employee-sponsored retirement plans.&lt;/p&gt;</rr:PerformanceTableNarrativeTextBlock>
  <rr:PerformanceTableHeading contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_Member">&lt;p&gt;Average Annual Total Returns for the Periods Ended December 31, 2017&lt;/p&gt;</rr:PerformanceTableHeading>
  <rr:MaximumSalesChargeImposedOnPurchasesOverOfferingPrice decimals="4" contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberC000105232_Member" unitRef="pure">0</rr:MaximumSalesChargeImposedOnPurchasesOverOfferingPrice>
  <rr:ManagementFeesOverAssets decimals="4" contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberC000105232_Member" unitRef="pure">0.0085</rr:ManagementFeesOverAssets>
  <rr:DistributionAndService12b1FeesOverAssets decimals="4" contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberC000105232_Member" unitRef="pure">0</rr:DistributionAndService12b1FeesOverAssets>
  <rr:OtherExpensesOverAssets decimals="4" contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberC000105232_Member" unitRef="pure">0</rr:OtherExpensesOverAssets>
  <rr:AcquiredFundFeesAndExpensesOverAssets decimals="4" contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberC000105232_Member" unitRef="pure">0.0003</rr:AcquiredFundFeesAndExpensesOverAssets>
  <rr:ExpensesOverAssets decimals="4" contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberC000105232_Member" unitRef="pure">0.0088</rr:ExpensesOverAssets>
  <rr:ExpenseExampleNoRedemptionYear01 decimals="INF" contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberC000105232_Member" unitRef="USD">90</rr:ExpenseExampleNoRedemptionYear01>
  <rr:ExpenseExampleNoRedemptionYear03 decimals="INF" contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberC000105232_Member" unitRef="USD">281</rr:ExpenseExampleNoRedemptionYear03>
  <rr:ExpenseExampleNoRedemptionYear05 decimals="INF" contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberC000105232_Member" unitRef="USD">488</rr:ExpenseExampleNoRedemptionYear05>
  <rr:ExpenseExampleNoRedemptionYear10 decimals="INF" contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberC000105232_Member" unitRef="USD">1084</rr:ExpenseExampleNoRedemptionYear10>
  <rr:PortfolioTurnoverRate decimals="4" contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_Member" unitRef="pure">1.1</rr:PortfolioTurnoverRate>
  <rr:AnnualReturn2014 decimals="4" contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberC000105232_Member" unitRef="pure">0.019</rr:AnnualReturn2014>
  <rr:AnnualReturn2015 decimals="4" contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberC000105232_Member" unitRef="pure">0.0031</rr:AnnualReturn2015>
  <rr:AnnualReturn2016 decimals="4" contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberC000105232_Member" unitRef="pure">0.0709</rr:AnnualReturn2016>
  <rr:AnnualReturn2017 decimals="4" contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberC000105232_Member" unitRef="pure">0.0285</rr:AnnualReturn2017>
  <rr:HighestQuarterlyReturnLabel contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberC000105232_Member">Best Quarter</rr:HighestQuarterlyReturnLabel>
  <rr:LowestQuarterlyReturnLabel contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberC000105232_Member">Worst Quarter</rr:LowestQuarterlyReturnLabel>
  <rr:BarChartHighestQuarterlyReturn decimals="4" contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberC000105232_Member" unitRef="pure">0.0217</rr:BarChartHighestQuarterlyReturn>
  <rr:BarChartHighestQuarterlyReturnDate contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberC000105232_Member">2016-03-31</rr:BarChartHighestQuarterlyReturnDate>
  <rr:BarChartLowestQuarterlyReturn decimals="4" contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberC000105232_Member" unitRef="pure">-0.0163</rr:BarChartLowestQuarterlyReturn>
  <rr:BarChartLowestQuarterlyReturnDate contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberC000105232_Member">2015-12-31</rr:BarChartLowestQuarterlyReturnDate>
  <rr:AverageAnnualReturnYear01 decimals="4" contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberC000105232_Member" unitRef="pure">0.0285</rr:AverageAnnualReturnYear01>
  <rr:AverageAnnualReturnSinceInception decimals="4" contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberC000105232_Member" unitRef="pure">0.0293</rr:AverageAnnualReturnSinceInception>
  <rr:AverageAnnualReturnInceptionDate contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberC000105232_Member">2013-05-01</rr:AverageAnnualReturnInceptionDate>
  <rr:AverageAnnualReturnYear01 decimals="4" contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberC000105232_MemberAftertaxondistributions_Member" unitRef="pure">0.0125</rr:AverageAnnualReturnYear01>
  <rr:AverageAnnualReturnSinceInception decimals="4" contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberC000105232_MemberAftertaxondistributions_Member" unitRef="pure">0.0127</rr:AverageAnnualReturnSinceInception>
  <rr:AverageAnnualReturnYear01 decimals="4" contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberC000105232_MemberAftertaxondistributionsandsaleoffundshares_Member" unitRef="pure">0.016</rr:AverageAnnualReturnYear01>
  <rr:AverageAnnualReturnSinceInception decimals="4" contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberC000105232_MemberAftertaxondistributionsandsaleoffundshares_Member" unitRef="pure">0.0147</rr:AverageAnnualReturnSinceInception>
  <rr:AverageAnnualReturnYear01 decimals="4" contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberMarkitiBoxxUSDLiquidLeveragedLoanIndex_Member" unitRef="pure">0.033</rr:AverageAnnualReturnYear01>
  <rr:AverageAnnualReturnSinceInception decimals="4" contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberMarkitiBoxxUSDLiquidLeveragedLoanIndex_Member" unitRef="pure">0.0303</rr:AverageAnnualReturnSinceInception>
  <rr:AverageAnnualReturnYear01 decimals="4" contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberSPLSTALeveragedLoan100Index_Member" unitRef="pure">0.02</rr:AverageAnnualReturnYear01>
  <rr:AverageAnnualReturnSinceInception decimals="4" contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_MemberSPLSTALeveragedLoan100Index_Member" unitRef="pure">0.0243</rr:AverageAnnualReturnSinceInception>
  <rr:AnnualFundOperatingExpensesTableTextBlock contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_Member">&lt;div style="display:none"&gt;~ http://www.ftportfolios.com/role/ScheduleAnnualFundOperatingExpenses000013 column period compact * ~&lt;/div&gt;</rr:AnnualFundOperatingExpensesTableTextBlock>
  <rr:BarChartTableTextBlock contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_Member">&lt;div style="display:none"&gt;~ http://www.ftportfolios.com/role/ScheduleAnnualTotalReturnsBarChart000016 column period compact * ~&lt;/div&gt;</rr:BarChartTableTextBlock>
  <rr:ExpenseExampleNoRedemptionTableTextBlock contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_Member">&lt;div style="display:none"&gt;~ http://www.ftportfolios.com/role/ScheduleExpenseExampleNoRedemptionTransposed000015 column period compact * ~&lt;/div&gt;</rr:ExpenseExampleNoRedemptionTableTextBlock>
  <rr:PerformanceTableTextBlock contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_Member">&lt;div style="display:none"&gt;~ http://www.ftportfolios.com/role/ScheduleAverageAnnualTotalReturnsTransposed000017 column period compact * ~&lt;/div&gt;</rr:PerformanceTableTextBlock>
  <rr:ShareholderFeesTableTextBlock contextRef="Duration_31Dec2018_31Dec2018S000034146_Member">&lt;div style="display:none"&gt;~ http://www.ftportfolios.com/role/ScheduleShareholderFees000012 column period compact * ~&lt;/div&gt;</rr:ShareholderFeesTableTextBlock>
</xbrl>
